Finding Aid for Gardner Ackley Papers, 1936-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- President's Council of Economic Advisers
  - Speeches and Presentations
    - Joint Luncheon, American Finance Association and the American Economic Association, New York City, "The Contributions of Economists to Policy Formation" December 29, 1965 (Box 9)
    - Economic Symposium on the occasion of the Twentieth Anniversary of the Employment Act of 1946, Washington. February 23, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Economic Club of Detroit. "Economic Problems and Prospects" February 28, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Kalamazoo, Michigan February 28, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Annual Business International Washington Roundtable March 8, 1966 (Box 9)
    - American Chamber of Commerce in Belgium, Brussels. "American Economic Policy: Yesterday and Today." March 17, 1966 (Box 9)
    - University of Texas, Austin April 14, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Baylor University, Waco Texas April 15, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Greater Boston Chamber of Commerce. April 21, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Executive Council of the American Bankers Association, White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia April 23, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Annual Convention, Supermarket Institute, Chicago April 27, 1966 (Box 10)
    - University of Chicago Conference, Chicago. "Guidelines, Informal Controls, and the Market Place" April 28, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Annual Meeting of the Chamber of Commerce of the United States, Washington. "The Businessman's Role in Fighting Inflation" May 2, 1966 (Box 10)
    - The Business Council, Hot Springs, Virginia May 12, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Commencement Address, The University of Michigan. "The Uses of Economic Knowledge" August 7, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Luncheon, The National Industrial Conference Board, New York City. "Business in 1967" October 6, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Southern Illinois University, Carbondale, Illinois. Vandeveer Memorial Lecture" October 26, 1966, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Luncheon, The National Public Advisory Committee on Regional Economic Development, Washington November 1, 1966 (Box 10)
    - The Business Council, Hot Springs, Virginia. "Tentative outline of Wage-Price Policy for 1967" December 8, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Industrial College of the Armed Forces, Washington February 7, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Swarthmore College. "Economics and Politics" March 5, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Calvin Bullock Forum, New York City April 4, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Senior Seminar in Foreign Policy, Department of State April 11, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Luncheon, Executive Directors, International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, Washington April 11, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Annual Convention, Edison Electric Institute, New Orleans. "The Economic Picture" April 17, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Symposium on "The Corporation and Social Responsibility" at the University of Illinois at Chicago Circle. Presentation entitled "The Corporation and Government: Private Enterprise and the Public Interest" April 20, 1967, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Annual Meeting, Society of American Business Writers, Washington. "The Death of the Guideposts" May 2, 1967 (Box 10)
    - Army War College, Carlisle, Pennsylvania. May 9, 1967 (Box 10)
    - G.M. Loeb Awards for Distinguished Business and Financial Journalism, New York City May 23, 1967, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Background Briefing at Foreign Correspondents Center of the United States Information Agency. New York City May 23, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Commencement Address, Kalamazoo College, Kalamazoo, Michigan. "The Meaning of Responsibility" June 11, 1967, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - National Petroleum Council, Washington July 13, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Annual Meeting, American Farm Economic Association and the Canadian Agricultural Economics Association, Guelph, Ontario. "U.S. Economic Developments and Policies and Their Impact on Agriculture" August 14, 1967, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - National Issues Conference. Sponsored by Congressman Frank Evans, Washington. September 11, 1967 (Box 11)
    - UPI Editors and Publishers Conference panel on "Where is the Economy Going and What Does It Mean". San Francisco September 19, 1967, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - The Business Council, Hot Springs, Virginia October 20, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Annual Business outlook Conference, Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce. "Dominant Factors in the Outlook for 1968" November 8, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Public Affairs Luncheon, Union League Club of Detroit November 10, 1967 (Box 11)
  - Television Appearances
    - ABC: "Issues and Answers" January 31, 1965 (Box 11)
    - CBS: "Alumni Fun" February 19, 1966 (Box 11)
    - NBC: "Meet the Press" March 27, 1966 (Box 11)
    - CBS: "Face the Nation" September 25, 1966 (Box 11)
  - Radio Interviews
    - Voice of America June 28, 1965 (Box 11)
    - Voice of America April 18, 1966 (Box 11)
  - Meetings of the Cabinet
    - General (Box 11)
    - November 1964-September 1967, 22 folders (Box 11)
  - Government Meetings Primarily Regarding Domestic Considerations
    - Federal, State and Local officials to discuss reduction of governmental expenditures May 2, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Meeting regarding lead and zinc prices July 6, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Regarding LMAC April 28, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Meeting of Quadriad with president June 5, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding purchase of generators for Grand Coulee Dam July 6, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding crude oil July 12, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding chemicals August 2, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices August 4, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding government insurance August 9, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding American Motors August 11, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices August 18, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices August 25, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices September 1, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices September 8, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices September 15, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices October 20, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices October 27, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices November 3, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices November 10, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices November 17, 1967 (Box 11)
    - Regarding prices November 24, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Regarding Workman's Compensation November 30, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Regarding prices December 1, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Regarding manpower December 12, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Regarding travel deficits December 20, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Balance of payments (Dillon Committee) January 9, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Government and Other Meetings Regarding International Considerations
    - Meeting with Secretary Rusk and others regarding visit of Japanese Prime Minister Sato January 8, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (hereafter OECD) Ministerial meeting, Paris December 2-3, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Economic Policy Committee (hereafter EPC) of OECD, Paris. February 17-18, 1965, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Visit of James Callaghan, Chancellor of the Exchequer, United Kingdom June 29, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Discussions between officials of the United States and the United Kingdom in London and meeting of EPC of OECD, Paris. July 2-9, 1965, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - EPC of OECD, Paris July 7-8, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Annual meeting, Board of Governors of the International Monetary Fund (hereafter IMF), International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD), International Finance Corporation (IFC) and International Development Association (IDA), Washington. September 26-October 1, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Meeting with Robert Marjolin, vice-president of the European Economic Community September 28, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Consultation with IMF officials, Washington. October 18, 1965 (Box 12)
    - EPC of OECD, Paris. November 3-10, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Meeting with Garcia Monco, Spanish Minister of Commerce and three others, Washington. December 5, 1966 (Box 12)
    - Joint meetings, U.S. and Canadian cabinets. June 20-22, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Meeting with Japanese Economic mission, Washington. June 30, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Meeting with Foreign graduate students arranged by the Washington International Center, Association Internationale des Etudiants en Sciences Economiques et Commerciales August 3, 1967 (Box 12)
    - IMF meeting, Rio de Janeiro September 22-October 1, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Meeting with European Investment Group, Washington October 14, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Meeting with Jean Ray, president of the commission of the European Communities, Washington February 7, 1968, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Background folder-Italy, Switzerland, Sweden, Netherlands, Canada, Japan, and Austria (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Meetings with non-Governmental persons or groups
    - Meetings with labor economists and research directors May 1964-November 1967, 6 folders (Box 12)
    - CEA Consultants December 1963-December 1967, 7 folders (Box 12)
    - Management Interns, Department of Labor February 19, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Delegation of Directors, Automobile Manufacturers Association December 3, 1964 (Box 12)
    - Ford Foundation-Government meeting April 7, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Kenneth C. Kellar May 26, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Summer Interns from the University of Michigan July 27, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Meeting regarding automobile scrap disposal September 22, 1965 (Box 12)
    - Leonard Coe Scruggs March 1, 1966 (Box 12)
    - Harold B. Dorsey April 29, 1966 (Box 12)
    - American Bankers Association Monetary Conference, Madrid May 23-28, 1966 (Box 12)
    - Paul Binder June 7, 1966 (Box 12)
    - Introduction for George Washington. Law Review Symposium December 1966 (Box 12)
    - Gridiron Club Dinner March 11, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Seminar on the Economy sponsored by the American Enterprise Institute April 11, 1967 (Box 12)
    - White House Correspondents Dinner April 28, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Sioux City, Iowa Chamber of Commerce May 3, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Harold Linder May 5, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Dinner with Mr. and Mrs. Baldwin Maull May 17, 1967 (Box 12)
    - "Young Economists" May 19, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Dinner with Mr. and Mrs. Gerald L. Phillippe June 6, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Meeting regarding nonferrous metals June 16, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Meeting regarding household appliances August 22, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Meeting regarding machinery industry August 31, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Meeting with Air Transportation Association September 8, 1967 (Box 12)
    - Meeting with steel industry September 12, 1967 (Box 13)
    - "Institute For the Future" October 5, 1967 (Box 13)
    - Reception for Jack Ashley January 5, 1968 (Box 13)
    - Luncheon for CIAP January 25, 1968 (Box 13)
    - Business Council Dinner February 14, 1968 (Box 13)
    - American Bankers Association Monetary Conference, Copenhagen May 21-24, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Memos
    - To the President November 1963-July 1966, 17 folders (Box 13)
    - To the President August 1966-February 1968, 19 folders (Box 14)
    - To the President regarding
      - International monetary problems (Box 14)
      - Profits (Box 14)
      - Railroad dispute (Box 14)
      - Senator Goldwater's tax plan (Box 14)
      - Impact of Senator Goldwater's tax plan on the stockmarket (Box 14)
      - Meeting with all past CEA chairmen (Box 14)
      - Secretary Fowler's proposals of March 22, 1966 (Box 14)
    - General memoranda June 1962-December 1962, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - General memoranda January 1963-October 1964, 13 folders (Box 15)
    - Memos and Correspondence with Vice-President and Cabinet officials (Box 15)
    - Memos to White House Staff
      - Francis Bator (Box 15)
      - McGeorge Bundy (Box 15)
      - Horace Busby (Box 15)
      - Joseph Califano August 1965-February 1968, 15 folders (Box 15)
      - Douglas Cater (Box 15)
      - George Christian (Box 15)
      - James C. Gaither (Box 15)
      - John Kenneth Galbraith (Box 15)
      - Ernest Goldstein (Box 15)
      - Seymour E. Harris (Box 15)
      - Charles Horsky (Box 16)
      - Jake Jacobsen (Box 16)
      - Robert Hardesty (Box 16)
      - Robert Kintner (Box 16)
      - Lawrence Levinson (Box 16)
      - Harry McPherson (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
      - Bill Moyers November 1964-1967, 8 folders (Box 16)
      - Lawrence O'Brien (Box 16)
      - Paul Popple (Box 16)
      - George Reedy (Box 16)
      - Paul Southwick (Box 16)
      - Jack Valenti (Box 16)
      - Marvin Watson (Box 16)
      - Lee White (Box 16)
      - Henry Wilson, Jr (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous Council of Economic Advisors Memos (Box 16)
  - Congressional Correspondence
    - Joseph B. Addabbo (Box 16)
    - Wayne N. Aspinall (Box 16)
    - Bert Bandstra (Box 16)
    - Birch Bayh (Box 16)
    - Page Belcher (Box 16)
    - Charles Bennett (Box 16)
    - Hale Boggs (Box 16)
    - Frances P. Bolton (Box 16)
    - Daniel B. Brewster (Box 16)
    - Jack Brooks (Box 16)
    - Gary Brown (Box 16)
    - James Burke (Box 16)
    - Clifford P. Case (Box 16)
    - Emmanuel Celler (Box 16)
    - Frank Church (Box 16)
    - Joseph S. Clark (Box 16)
    - Jeffery Cohelan (Box 16)
    - Barber Conable (Box 16)
    - Silvio O. Conte (Box 16)
    - John C. Culver (Box 16)
    - Thomas B. Curtis (Box 16)
    - Glenn R. Davis (Box 16)
    - John H. Dent (Box 16)
    - Samuel L. Devine (Box 16)
    - Robert Duncan (Box 16)
    - Paul H. Douglas (Box 16)
    - John G. Dow (Box 16)
    - John J. Duncan (Box 16)
    - Joshua Eilberg (Box 16)
    - Robert F. Ellsworth (Box 16)
    - Sam Ervin, Jr (Box 16)
    - Frank E. Evans (Box 16)
    - Joe L. Evins (Box 16)
    - George Fallon (Box 16)
    - Billie S. Farnum (Box 16)
    - Dante B. Fascell (Box 16)
    - Michael A. Feighan (Box 16)
    - Hiram Fong (Box 16)
    - Gerald Ford (Box 16)
    - James Fulton (Box 16)
    - Robert N. Giaimo (Box 16)
    - Charles S. Gubser (Box 16)
    - Charles A. Halleck (Box 16)
    - Lee H. Hamilton (Box 16)
    - Richard T. Hanna (Box 16)
    - Clifford P. Hansen (Box 16)
    - John R. Hansen (Box 16)
    - Philip A. Hart (Box 16)
    - Vance Hartke (Box 16)
    - Mark Hatfield (Box 16)
    - Carl Hayden (Box 16)
    - Margaret Heckler (Box 16)
    - Lister Hill (Box 16)
    - Spessard L. Holland (Box 16)
    - Roman Hruska (Box 16)
    - Hubert H. Humphrey (Box 16)
    - Donald J. Irwin (Box 16)
    - Henry Jackson (Box 16)
    - Jacob Javits (Box 16)
    - Paul C. Jones (Box 16)
    - Robert E. Jones (Box 16)
    - Joseph E. Karth (Box 16)
    - Robert W. Kastenmeier (Box 16)
    - Edward Kennedy (Box 16)
    - Robert Kennedy (Box 16)
    - Robert S. Kerr (Box 16)
    - Melvin Laird (Box 16)
    - Frank J. Lausche (Box 16)
    - Clarence D. Long (Box 16)
    - Edward V. Long (Box 16)
    - Russell B. Long (Box 16)
    - John C. McClellan (Box 17)
    - Robert C. McEwan (Box 17)
    - Gale McGee (Box 17)
    - Clark MacGregor (Box 17)
    - George McGovern (Box 17)
    - Thomas G. McGraith, Jr (Box 17)
    - Roy H. McVicker (Box 17)
    - Warren G. Magnuson (Box 17)
    - William S. Mailliard (Box 17)
    - Charles Mathias (Box 17)
    - Robert Michel (Box 17)
    - Wilbur D. Mills (Box 17)
    - Patsy T. Mink (Box 17)
    - William E. Minshall (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Walter F. Mondale (Box 17)
    - A.S. Mike Monroney (Box 17)
    - William S. Moorhead (Box 17)
    - F. Bradford Morse (Box 17)
    - Wayne Morse (Box 17)
    - Frank E. Moss (Box 17)
    - Karl Mundt (Box 17)
    - George Murphy (Box 17)
    - Gaylord Nelson (Box 17)
    - Barratt O'Hara (Box 17)
    - Richard L. Ottinger (Box 17)
    - Anthony Pascal (Box 17)
    - John Pastore (Box 17)
    - Wright Patman (Box 17)
    - James P. Pearson (Box 17)
    - Clairborne Pell (Box 17)
    - Claude Pepper (Box 17)
    - Charles Percy (Box 17)
    - William Proxmire (Box 17)
    - Roman Pucinski (Box 17)
    - John A. Race (Box 17)
    - Jennings Randolph (Box 17)
    - Henry S. Reuss (Box 17)
    - Abraham Ribicoff (Box 17)
    - Paul G. Rogers (Box 17)
    - Benjamin S. Rosenthal (Box 17)
    - Richard L. Roudebush (Box 17)
    - Donald Russell (Box 17)
    - Richard B. Russell (Box 17)
    - William F. Ryan (Box 17)
    - James H. Scheuer (Box 17)
    - Richard S. Schweiker (Box 17)
    - Fred Schwengel (Box 17)
    - Carlton R. Sickles (Box 17)
    - George Smathers (Box 17)
    - William Spong (Box 17)
    - Robert G. Sweeney (Box 17)
    - Roy A. Taylor (Box 17)
    - Herbert Tenzer (Box 17)
    - Paul H. Todd (Box 17)
    - John V. Tunney (Box 17)
    - Joseph Tydings (Box 17)
    - Morris Udall (Box 17)
    - Al Ullman (Box 17)
    - Charles A. Vanik (Box 17)
    - Weston Vivian (Box 17)
    - Charles Weltner (Box 17)
    - Harrison A. Williams, Jr (Box 17)
    - William B. Widnall (Box 17)
    - John J. Williams (Box 17)
    - Wendall Wyatt (Box 17)
    - John W. Wydler (Box 17)
    - Ralph W. Yarborough (Box 17)
    - Clement J. Zablocki (Box 17)
    - Roger H. Zion (Box 17)
    - Regarding export of black walnut logs (Box 17)
    - Regarding REA Loans (Box 17)
  - State Governors Correspondence: with
    - Jack M. Campbell, governor of New Mexico (Box 17)
    - William L. Guy, governor of North Dakota (Box 17)
    - Philip H. Hoff, governor of Vermont (Box 17)
  - News Media Articles and Interviews, Invitations, and Miscellaneous
    - Associated Press (Box 17)
    - Business Week (Box 17)
    - Detroit News (Box 17)
    - Dun's Review (Box 17)
    - Fairchild Publications (Box 17)
    - Fortune Forecasts (Box 17)
    - Finish Press-background briefing for (Box 17)
    - France: Enterprise Iron Age (Box 17)
    - Japan: Toyo Keizai (Box 17)
    - Labor Trends (Box 17)
    - McCall Corporation Editorial Committee (Box 17)
    - National Broadcasting Company (Box 17)
    - National Educational Radio (Box 17)
    - Nations Business (Box 17)
    - News background luncheon (Box 17)
    - Newsweek (Box 17)
    - New York Times (Box 17)
    - Silver Quill Awards (Box 17)
    - Steel (Box 17)
    - Time (Box 17)
    - United Press International (Box 17)
    - U.S. News and World Report (Box 18)
    - Wall Street Journal (Box 18)
    - Washington Post (Box 18)
    - Schedule of Invitations November 1964-December 1967, 7 folders (Box 18)
    - Schedule of Engagements (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous personal items (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous personal correspondence (Box 18)
    - Gardner Ackley Oral History Interview (Box 18)
    - Oral history interview 1978 (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings (Box 18)
    - Negative microfilm copy of Gardner Ackley's President's Council of Economic Advisors papers, 20 microfilms (Box 23)
      [Staff use only; not currently available for inter-library loan.]
- University of Michigan Files
  The University of Michigan series is alphabetically arranged by subject. About half of this material pertains to lecture notes and exams for courses which Ackley taught. The rest of this series includes drafts of speeches, journal articles, and book reviews which were written while Ackley was a professor of economics at the University of Michigan. In addition, Ackley's files relating to his participation on the Rackham Review Committee (1974-1976) are included in this series. Miscellaneous correspondence with the Economics Department and with the University of Michigan is also included.
  - 1930s-1950s
    - Course materials
      - Economics 152-252-Final Exams: 1947 (Box 18)
      - Economics 153-Lecture Notes and Exams: 1950 (Box 18)
      - Economics 153-Lecture Notes (Box 18)
      - Economics 163-Lecture Notes: 1940 (Box 18)
      - Lecture Notes: 1937 (Box 18)
      - Economics 386-Lecture Notes: 1950 (Box 18)
      - Economics 164-Lecture Notes: Fall 1948 (Box 18)
      - Economics 364-Lecture Notes: 1950-1951 (Box 18)
      - Business Administration 271-Lecture Notes (Box 18)
      - Business Administration 100-Lecture Notes and Exams (Box 18)
      - Lecture Notes: 1937-1938 (Box 18)
      - Economics 257: Lecture Notes: Fall 1957 (Box 18)
      - Economics 141: Business Control Notes: 1941 (Box 18)
      - Economics 164: Lecture Notes and Exams: 1947 (Box 18)
      - Lecture Notes: Technology (Box 18)
      - Economics 163: Lecture Notes: 1950 (Box 18)
      - Economics 163-Bibliography (Box 18)
      - Economics-Notes (Box 18)
      - Examination File (Box 19)
      - Economics 196 and 296-Lecture Notes (Box 19)
      - Economics 296-Lecture Notes: Summer 1954 (Box 19)
      - Economics 164, 5 folders (Box 19)
      - Economics 195-Lecture notes and Exams: 1938 (Box 19)
      - Theory of Production and Costs (Box 19)
      - Mathematical Economics and Mathematical Models (Box 19)
      - Oligopoly: 1940 (Box 19)
      - Economics 386-Lecture Notes: Spring 1956 (Box 19)
      - Economics 151-251-Articles, Reprints, Pamphlets (Box 19)
      - Economics 296-Exams: 1953-1954 (Box 19)
      - Economics 196-Exams: 1948-1950 (Box 19)
      - Economics 296-Lecture Notes: 1950 (Box 19)
      - Economics 196-Lecture Notes: Spring-Summer 1948 (Box 19)
      - Economics 151 (Box 19)
      - Economics 296-Lecture Notes: Fall 1952 (Box 19)
      - Economics 196-Course Outlines: 1946-1950 (Box 19)
      - Economics 164-Final Exams: 1947-1949 (Box 19)
      - Economics 257-Exams: 1957-1961 (Box 19)
      - Economics 151-Lecture Notes and Exams: 1948 (Box 19)
      - Economics 257-Lecture Notes and Exams: Summer 1956 (Box 19)
      - Economics 175 1937-1947 (Box 19)
      - Economics 296-Notes: 1952 (Box 19)
      - Economics 151-Notes: 1947 (Box 19)
      - Economics 153-Notes: 1947 (Box 19)
      - Economics 51-Notes: 1946 (Box 19)
      - Economics 151-251-Notes: Summer 1947 (Box 19)
      - Economics 151-251-Notes on Keynes: Summer 1947 (Box 19)
      - Economics 151-251-Bibliographies, Exams, Misc (Box 19)
      - Economics 151-251-Lecture notes: 1947 (Box 19)
      - Economics 152-Notes (Box 19)
      - Economics 133-Notes, Exams: 1937 (Box 19)
      - Economics 400-Economic History of Europe (Box 19)
      - Labor Problems (Box 19)
      - Ph.D Preliminary Public Finance Examination Notes (Box 20)
      - Economics 351-Lecture Notes: 1955 (Box 20)
      - Economics 151-252-Lecture Notes: Spring 1954 (Box 20)
      - Economics 175-Lecture Notes (Box 20)
      - Economics 151-252-Lecture Notes: Spring 1948 (Box 20)
      - Antimonopoly Information (Box 20)
      - Doctoral Preliminary Examination Sample Questions (Box 20)
      - Economics 151-251-Lecture Notes (Box 20)
      - Economics 151-251-Lecture Notes and Exams: 1950 (Box 20)
      - Economics 175-Lecture notes: 1946 (Box 20)
      - Ph.D. Preliminary Examination Notes (Box 20)
      - Economics 296-Lecture Notes and Exams (Box 20)
      - Economics 151-252-Lecture Notes: Summer 1947 (Box 20)
      - Economics 152-252-Lecture Notes: Summer 1955 (Box 20)
      - Economics 196-Lecture Notes: 1947 (Box 20)
      - Economics 152-252: 1955 (Box 20)
      - Lecture Notes (Box 20)
      - Economics 296-Lecture Notes: 1950 (Box 20)
      - Economics 296-Lecture Notes: Summer 1953 (Box 20)
      - Ph.D. Preliminary Examination Notes (Box 20)
      - Ph.D. Preliminary Examination Notes (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous research, reviews and study files
      (include research on Italian economy)
      - Project on Industrial Structure of Southern Italy (Box 20)
      - Review of Bruno Jossa Interesse, monetu e credite (Box 20)
      - Problems of Economic Development in Southern Italy (Box 20)
      - Post World War II Italian Economy, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Notes on Current Trends in Italian Economy (Box 20)
      - Notes on conversations regarding Italian economy 1955 (Box 20)
      - Notes on readings about Italian economy: 1956 (Box 20)
      - Memos and Drafts regarding Italy 1956-1957 (Box 20)
      - Trip to Italy: 1957 (Box 20)
      - Paper "Financial Controls and Monopolistic Influences as They Effect Location" by Gardner Ackley: 1941 (Box 20)
      - Review of Income, Saving and the Theory of Consumer Behavior by James Duesenberry (Box 20)